-= CHD字幕组 原创翻译 =-
字幕仅供翻译学习交流 谢绝用于任何商业用途
翻译：dengpao 校对：dahongying
我绝不找借口
I'm not gonna make excuses.
所有的一切
I asked for this.
皆我所自愿
All of it.
因为我想出人头地
And I did it to become s omeone else.
我渴求更多
I wanted more.
我们这一代人
We belong to a generation
是看着我们的未来被偷去的一代
that watched our future get stolen out from under us.
父辈所崇尚的美国梦已经被那些…
The American Dream our parents knew has been hijacked by men
既得利益者坑蒙拐骗
who are willing to lie, cheat and steal to protect their wealth.
曾经只需学习好
Used to be if you got good grades,
便可以进好学校
you got into the right school,
找一份不错的工作
got the right job.
再辛苦工作15年
And after 15 years of hard work,
某个一官半职
you get your name on the door.
但这样的世界已不复存在
But that world is gone.
人们总是告诫你美梦易破
People always tell you be careful what you wish for.
我从不相信他们
I never believed them.
对岸的灯火总是更亮
The lights always looked brighter across the river.
片名：偏执
快下来
Hey, come on!
我来了 切尔
Hey, I'm coming. Chill.
要付额外的钱吗？
I'm paying extra for that?
别担心 免费的医保 斯科特
Don't worry, it's covered, Scout.
- 没有免费的午餐 老爸  - 你去哪？
- Nothing's covered, Dad. - Where you going?
我和凯文去俱乐部
I'm going to the club with Kev.
- 谁？  - 你又不认识他？
- Which one? - Why? You think you might know it?
我小年轻的时候可是迪厅名角
Well, I have been known to frequent discotheques in my heyday.
现在不兴这种叫法 但你挺行啊
They don't call them that anymore, but that's good.
别让他吸烟
Hey, don't let him smoke.
他常把烟藏靠垫下
He hides cigars under that cushion there.
别吸了
Don't smoke!
怎么了 你嫉妒啊？
What's the matter? You jealous?
你猜对了
Oh, yes.
去RISE俱乐部 你怎么这么久？
Club Rise, baby. What took you so long?
帮个忙让我们进去
Why don't you do yourself a favor and lift the rope?
关我什么事？
And how is that doing me a favor?
算是投资好了
Consider it an investment.
周一我俩会挣到足够的钱
Come Monday, my boy and I will be making so much money,
到时候你准得求我们
you'll be begging us to come back
帮你完成月营业计划
to this flavor of the month of yours.
潮人禁止 处男禁止
Look, no hipsters and no virgins.
处男？
Virgin?
他不是处男  我刚看到他劈腿了
He's not a virgin. I just watched him get laid outside.
亲眼所见 绝对的大劈腿
I watched it, I literally saw him get laid.
- 亚当 走吧  - 亲眼所见
- Adam, come on. - I saw him with my own eyes.
我会回来的
I'm going to be back.
你很紧张？
Are you nervous yet?
你紧张什么？
Nervous? About what?
周一得把产品展示给怪胎尼古拉斯·怀特
On Monday we pitch our product to Nicolas freaking Wyatt,
所以嘛
that's what.
凯文 我们已经为此忙活了4个月
Kevin, we've been working on that pitch for four months.
这件天才产品
It's genius.
我唯一担心的是
The only thing I'm worried about is
如果我们没有因此被提职 怀特会炒谁的鱿鱼
who Wyatt's gonna fire for not promoting us sooner.
有能力付账单真开心
How great is it gonna be to pay our bills
还要大吃大喝
and eat in the same month?
准备过好日子吧
Oh, get ready 'cause it's happening.
每次你一预言
You always say it's happening,
我就得付出租车费
and then I end up paying for the cab.
这次不同
This time's different.
将会改变我们的一生
This pitch, it's gonna change our lives.
发誓
Promise you.
总之还是得我付车费吧？
But I'm still paying for the cab, right?
- 对  - 就知道
- Yeah. - Got you.
不是我的
It's not me.
喂
Hello?
我马上到
Yeah, I'll be right there.
能拐一下吗？
Sir, can you turn around?
去圣爵士医院
We need to go to Saint Joe's Hospital.
亚当 他好得很
Adam, he's doing great.
还是老毛病 对面那间
He's up to his old tricks. He's right through there.
我们帮他疏通了积液 行了
We cleared out the mucus, and he's fine.
但他需要更多的吸氧
But he must use the oxygen more,
一旦栓塞 立刻叫医生
and he has to call us at the onset of congestion.
- 他知道的  - 如他所愿吧
- Yeah, he knows. - Wants to do it his own way, huh?
对
Yeah.
- 你可以带他回家了  - 好的 谢谢
- You can take him home. - All right. Thanks.
你看 坎西迪先生
As you can see, Mr. Cassidy,
最后两个疗程不在保险范围内
the last two procedures were not covered by insurance.
你意思我需要额外付钱？
What do you mean? I have extended coverage.
说的没错 怀特公司已停止支付了
You did. Wyatt Corp terminated it.
他们不应该那么做 这是我应得的福利
They can't do that. I have it. I need to have it.
很不幸 他们有这个权利
Unfortunately, they can.
现在很多公司都这么削减开支
A lot of our companies are doing it now, cutbacks.
我连40块都没有
I don't have 40 grand.
我们可以为您设计一套还款计划或医疗贷款
We can help with a payment plan, or a medical loan.
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
没关系 我想别的办法吧
Yeah. I'll figure something out.
（基于约瑟夫方德同名小说改编）
我们已经尽力 请理解
We did everything we could.
我们为怀特公司卖命
We work for Wyatt Corp,
世界顶级科技公司之一
one of the top tech companies on the planet.
初入茅庐的我们决心一展宏图
When they hired us, we were going to take over the world.
六年过去了 我们还是原地踏步
Six years in, we were still just lowly cubicle drones,
眼巴巴看着高层们捞足油水…
watching our bosses take home obscene bonuses...
…我们只拿可怜的底薪
...while we were stuck with entry-level salaries.
太久了 也该轮到我们了
We'd waited long enough. It was our turn.
是金子终于会闪光
Our time to shine.
你还好吗
You all right?
很好 我们去搞定他
Yeah. We're gonna kill it.
如果事情要黄
Yeah, well, if things go south,
也得冷静 对吗？
just stay cool. All right?
好的
Yeah.
怀特先生准备好了
Mr. Wyatt is ready.
冷静
Stay cool.
早上好
Good morning.
我们一直致力于沟通研究
We are all in the business of connecting people.
水不够热
This water's not hot enough.
抱歉 怀特先生 我来处理
I'm sorry, Mr. Wyatt. I'll take care of it.
需要再加热一下
It should be boiling.
喔… 我们一直致力于沟通研究
Uh... We're in the business of connecting people.
这句你说过了
You already said that.
是 这就是我们的客户所需求的
Right. That's what our customers have always wanted.
保持即时联络
To stay connected.
他们更多地使用键盘交谈
Those same customers are now texting
而不是面对面
more than they're talking
花在微博的时间超过了面谈
and tweeting more than they're meeting.
哪个环节出错了 我们有没有疏忽？
So, what's changed? What are we missing?
关键在于人们并不需要随时保持联络
We don't want to be connected anymore.
只希望在孤独的时候才联络
We just want to feel connected while we isolate.
因此…假如
So, what if...
…一个4寸的手机有个60寸的屏幕？
...a four-inch mobile had a 60-inch screen?
那就不是手机了
Well, then it wouldn't be mobile.
使用语音激活
With a voice-activated pairing device,
Ethion将可以…
Ethion will allow users
把手机屏幕广播到家中任意显示器上
to broadcast their mobile across any monitor in the home.
联机
Pick up.
Ethion 3.0 世界在你眼前
Ethion 3.0 gives you the power to bring your world to you.
他在向我推销软件？
Is he pitching me software?
先生 这个绝佳的机会在于:
Sir, we see a unique opportunity
Ethion可以运行在任何普通手机上…
to take Ethion from a run-of-the-mill phone...
这有悖于我们的品牌战略
This is a re-branding meeting.
说说疏忽吧？
Where's the disconnect?
先生 我认为疏忽在你与客户之间
Well, sir, I believe the disconnect is between you and the consumers.
你雇我们肯定不是为看你沏茶的吧？
You didn't hire us to sit around and watch you make tea, did you?
说说我为什么要雇你
Tell me, why did I hire you?
因为我们知道年轻人要什么
Because we know what a younger generation wants.
要什么？
Which is?
要的不是一部外表崭新的手机
A phone that doesn't just look new a phone that is new,
而是一部可以改变生活方式的手机
a phone that changes the way we live.
没错 我和你们年轻一代有代沟
You know, you're right. I have lost touch with your generation.
对不起忘了你叫什么名字
What was your name again?
亚当·坎西迪
I'm Adam Cassidy.
多大？
How old are you?
27岁
Twenty-seven.
我比你年轻两岁的时候
When I was two years younger than you are now,
已经开始摆弄数字蜂窝技术
I was pioneering digital cellular technology
而我同学们还在摆弄电子脉冲
while my colleagues were still pissing around with electronic pulses.
我有远见
I had vision.
但是你只有科技想象力
But you have all the technological advantage imaginable
你带给我的是什么？
and what do you bring me?
在电视上进行网络社交？
Social networking on a television.
下一个！ 理查德·麦卡利斯特
Next! Bring in Richard McAllister.
抱歉了 哥们
I'm sorry, guys.
你让我们像傻子一样矗着
You just left us standing there looking like idiots.
你脑子里到底想什么？
I mean, what were you thinking?
我们都力挺这个点子
We all backed the idea.
点子不是问题
Our idea wasn't the problem.
我揶揄了他 都看到他脸色了吧
I railroaded him. You saw his face.
领队发疯 与上帝作对就是这个下场
That's what happens when your team leader goes rogue and argues with God.
看来我们不会继续共事了
Well, uh... I guess now that we're not working together
这样我们就可以发展床上恋情了吧？
we can start sleeping together, right?
我真心希望你在开玩笑
I seriously hope you're not talking to me.
我们会找到新工作的吧？
We'll find new jobs, right?
我们不是离职的 是被解雇的
We weren't laid off, Chels. We were fired.
你准备在简历上怎么解释？
How are you going to explain that on your resume?
知道么？
You know what?
至少我可以请大家先喝一杯
The least I can do is buy you guys a few drinks.
用开发基金帐户？真的吗？
Our discretionary account? Really?
亚当 不要
Adam, no.
如果公司一旦发现我们还继续花钱…
If Wyatt ever found out that we spent any more money...
再坏还能怎么坏？ 再解雇我们一次？
What are they going to do? Fire us?
钱本来就是让我们见机行事的
The money was ours to spend as we see fit.
去RISE俱乐部
We're going to Rise.
- 我们进不去  - 我们可以
- We can't get in there. - Yes, we can.
- 我们可以  - 劝劝那家伙吧
- Yes, we can. - Try and stop the guy.
我们要去RISE
宝贝！ 太棒了！
We're going to Rise, baby! Oh, yeah!
伙计 这简直太酷了
Dude, you realize this is going to be so awesome.
- 我们要一醉方休  - 如何？
- We're going to pop ten bottles. - Think so?
我讨厌那条看门狗
I hate this doorman.
亚当·坎西迪 说了我会回来的
Adam Cassidy. Told you I'd be back.
你们的桌子在这边 先生
Your table's right this way, sir.
太好了！
Yeah!
太棒了
- 干！  - 干！
- Shots! - Shots!
- 干！  - 上帝啊
- Shots! - Oh my God.
今晚还不走运
if you guys don't get lucky tonight,
以后就别想了
it's never going to happen.
我负责倒酒 你要来一份吗？
I'm fielding offers. You want in?
待会见
See me after.
干杯 伙计们！
Cheers, guys!
亚当 桌上的酒快没了
Adam, maybe we should close out the tab.
别担心
Hey, don't worry about it, man, don't worry about it.
我们能再来一瓶诗珞珂吗？
(全球百大高档烈酒品牌)
Hey, can we get another bottle of Ciroc?
- 绕着我跳！  - 不 不 不
- Twirl me! - No, no, no.
来吧！
Come on!
伙计 你去哪儿
Hey, buddy, where you going?
走桃花运了
Could be love.
醒醒
Wake up.
Hey, wake up.
我得走了
I have to go.
你也该走了
So do you.
没早餐吗？
No breakfast?
我做错什么了吗？
Did I, uh, do something wrong?
要是你做错了
If you had done something wrong,
你不可能还在这里
you wouldn't be here, would you?
那么…
So...
那么 我们…
So, uh, we...
…走吧
...are leaving.
等一下 我都不知道你叫什么
Wait a second, I don't even know your name.
你是要走消防梯吗？
Are you taking the fire escape?
好的
OK.
- 谢谢  - 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
清咖还是加糖奶咖？
Hey. Black, or cream and sugar?
你跟踪我？
You stalking me now?
我只是想问问你叫什么
I just want to know your name.
你泡我 向我示好就是了电话号码？
Why? So you can poke me, friend me, ask for my number?
是的 给一个联系方式吧
Or you could just give me your number.
你不是我的菜
You're not relationship material.
菜？你想要长久关系？
Relationship? You're looking for a relationship?
我喜欢长久关系 我很在行
I love relationships. I'm great at relationships.
不 实际上我只想赶紧甩掉你
No. Actually, I'm just trying to get rid of you nicely.
我们炒饭了吗？
Didn't we have sex?
我喝醉的时候更中意桥那边的人
I have a thing for bridge-and-tunnel guys when I drink.
你刚才叫我桥那边的人？
Did you just call me bridge-and-tunnel?
你带我去吃芝士薯条
You took me out for cheese fries.
芝士薯条！
Cheese fries!
然后呢？
Oh. Then what?
然后一夜情呗
Then you had the night of your life.
你的原话
Your words, not mine.
清咖
Oh... Black.
（16条未读短信）
亚当·坎西迪？我是迈尔斯·米彻姆
Adam Cassidy? My name is Miles Meachum.
怀特先生想和你聊聊
Mr. Wyatt would like to speak with you.
你怎么知道我在这里？
How did you know where I was?
我都不住这附近的
I mean, I don't even live around here.
坎西迪先生
Mr. Cassidy.
自称比我还了解我生意的人
The man who claims he knows my business better than I do.
请坐吧
Here, take a seat.
- 来杯葡萄酒？  - 不
- Drop of vino? - Uh... No.
看来你是我们帐务漏洞的受益者
It seems you were the beneficiary of an accounting error we made.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
Ethion开发基金帐户
The Ethion discretionary fund.
我的钱用在哪里了？
Where's my money?
用于市场研究调研报告
We used it on market research.
调研RISE俱乐部？
At Club Rise?
1万6千美元？
Sixteen grand?
看来这份调研报告必然很详尽
It must be a very detailed report.
你认为你能侥幸成功么？
You think you can rip me off and get away with it?
信用卡诈骗
Credit card fraud?
不 对不起 我会还回来的
No, sir, I'm sorry. I'm gonna pay you back.
不行 这又不是贷款
No you won't. It wasn't a loan.
给你两条路
Now there's two ways we can play this.
做马还是做狗？
Are you a horse or a dog?
马是恐惧被鞭笞而飞奔
A horse is motivated by fear. He's running from the whip.
这鞭子就是信用卡诈骗
The whip here being felony fraud.
- 他是狗  - 狗是被饥饿而驱使
- He's a dog. - A dog is motivated by hunger.
他追踪兔子作为下一顿美食
He's chasing the rabbit, his next meal.
你在布鲁克林低收入家庭长大
You were raised in a low-income home in Brooklyn.
七岁的时候妈妈死了
Your mother died when you were seven.
税务显示你还要赡养老父
Your W-2 says you now support your father.
那？
30?
那意味着你每天都要翻过跨海大桥
So, it means you came across that bridge every day
渴望成功
hungry to succeed.
- 人都想成功  - 但并非人人可以像我们这样
- Everyone wants to succeed. - Yeah, but not like us.
你父亲做了32年保安
Your father spent 32 years as a security guard.
- 那行业能有什么雄心壮志？  - 这到底在干嘛？
- Where's the ambition in that? - What's this about?
你渴求更多！
You want more out of life!
我曾经和你一样 只不过来自不同的街区
I grew up like you. I mean, different streets.
怀着相同的梦 但没人会替我实现 没人
Same dream, but nobody gave it to me. No one.
我说我能让你发财如何 ？
And what if I told you I could make you rich?
让你朋友们重新获得工作？
And give your friends their jobs back?
你昨天展示了一个绝佳的创意
That was a smart pitch you gave yesterday.
我从艾康公司起家
I started out at Eikon.
乔克·戈达是我的师傅
Jock Goddard was my mentor.
你知道他吗
Do you know him?
是的 我当然知道
Yeah, of course I know him.
我的毕业论文是半导体内存研究
I did my graduate thesis on semi-conductor memory.
当时戈达要求手机不超过砖块大小
Goddard's basically the reason cell phones aren't the size of bricks.
他创建了艾康公司
He founded Eikon.
并最终成功上市
And built it into the largest publicly traded
成为全世界最大的科技公司
technology company in the world.
自从我独立门户后
And ever since I left, he has spent
他无时不刻不想摧毁我
every waking moment trying to destroy me.
艾康公司马上要发布一款力挽狂澜的新智能手机
Eikon has a new smartphone coming that's said to be a game-changer.
代号Occura
They're calling it Occura.
你要去艾康公司工作
You are going to work for Eikon.
- 什么？  - 帮我们得到想要的 你可得50万
- What? - Get us in the door, you get 500K.
成功之后 你会得到100万股权
Get us what we need, you'll see another million in stock options.
那笔数目
Money like that
足以让你安心照顾你父亲
would allow you to take care of your father and a whole lot more.
艾康公司不会雇佣我的
Eikon's not just going to hire me.
他们会 我们已经安排妥当
They will when we're done with you.
窃取商业机密是违法的
This is illegal. It's stealing trade secrets.
这就是你一直在等待的机会
This is the opportunity you have been waiting for.
不仅能让你夜夜笙歌
Now, you could have done a lot of things
一如昨晚
with that credit card last night.
而且还能支付你父亲的医疗保险费
Your father's health insurance premium,
及学业贷款
graduate school loans,
可你决定搬出群居屋
but you decided to take your mates out on the town,
住市中心的独立大宅
living it large.
因为你必须熟悉另一半人的生活
Because you want to know how the other half lives.
另一半人即我们富人！
We are the other half!
这些我都能替你办到
That's what I'm offering you.
如果我拒绝呢？
If I say no?
你和你朋友们将受到最严厉的法律追究
You and your friends will be prosecuted to the full extent of the law.
你不会只想坐着
And you don't want to sit around
看我沏茶吧？
and watch me make tea, do you?
你谁啊 电视警察？
What are you, the TV police?
- 你睡着了  - 我只是闭闭眼
- You were asleep. - My eyes were closed.
你去哪？
Where you going?
公司放假
I caught a break at the company.
放假 哪种假？
A break, what kind of break?
足够支付房租
A kind of break that pays our rent
和护士费用的假
and keeps your pretty nurse around.
是培训来着 我整个周末都要忙
It's a training thing, so I'll be gone all weekend.
今天周五
It's Friday night.
不是说好去本齐奥吃披萨喝啤酒的吗？
I thought we were going to Benzio's for pizza and beer.
我要去上班了 爸爸
I got to work, Dad.
如此才能飞黄腾达
That's how you climb the ladder in this business.
就因为你比手下干得更卖力
You work harder than the guy below you.
结果只能干一辈子的苦力保安
Otherwise you get stuck doing the same job your whole life.
听着
Look...
这些钱给你电话定餐 好吗？
Here's some money. You can order in, OK?
不要 多谢
No, no. Thanks.
好了
All right.
你具体在公司做什么 朱迪斯？
What exactly do you do for the company, Judith?
我有行为心理学的博士学位
I have a PhD in behavioral psychology.
能告诉你为什么你至今尚未成功
I can take one look at you and tell you why you haven't succeeded.
不如敞开天窗说亮话吧？
Why don't you tell me how you really feel?
我有各种方式能令你…
I can give you the tools to ascend
跻身全美的上流社会
to the highest ranks of corporate America.
但首先你得端正态度
But you have to lose the attitude.
这边
This way.
我带你去房间
I'll show you to your room.
初次见面时
When we meet someone,
形成所谓的第一印象
an immediate cognitive process takes place.
通常会以貌取人
We construct our first ideas on them based on their appearance.
所以你要想被人接受
So, if you want to be accepted,
就必须洞窥其中
you have to look the part.
融入并进入他们的生活
You have to fit in to get in.
怀特和戈达间发生了什么事？
What happened with Wyatt and Goddard?
乔克戈达是个聪明的生意人
Jack's a brilliant businessman.
他总是能够在他的产品中
He was always able to imbue his products
融入许多神奇的理念
with a magic of big ideas,
而怀特则是大脑
but Wyatt was the brains.
没有他的设计
Without his designs,
再神奇的理念都不能付诸实现
none of it would have been possible.
听起来是完美的搭档啊
Hmm. Sounds like a perfect pairing.
对戈达 算是
For Goddard, yes.
怀特献出了一生中最好的时光
Wyatt gave him the best years of his life.
乔克戈达失去了儿子迪兰 因为服毒过量
Jock lost his son Dylan to a drug overdose.
所以 如果你谈到失去母亲…
So, if you talk about losing your mother...
不 我不会的
No, I won't.
会勾起他的回忆 趁机说你缺少父爱
Then, appeal to his void. Say you had no father figure.
我父亲还健在
I have a father.
你不想成为像他一样的人
You don't aspire to be like him.
信任的手段在于…
Which brings us to trust.
要使人信服 必须首先成为他
If you can convince him that you're just like him,
与之同信仰
that you share the same beliefs as him,
此乃信任的根源
it will engender trust.
信任是商业间谍的必杀技
And trust is the holy grail of espionage.
她说得轻巧
She makes it sound so easy.
在我没有成功之前
But this is a man who recognized me
这男人就认识我
for who I was years before I did.
与我走的很近
He kept me close
是因为对敌的策略
because that's what you do with an enemy.
在我焦躁不安的时候 他允诺我担任合伙人
When I got restless, he promised me partnership.
真是天才
It was genius.
在事业即将成功的时候
I saw the finish line
把我所有的金点子都给了他…
and I gave him every good idea I ha...
- 他是谁？  - 新裁缝
- Who's this? - He's the new tailor.
我是乔治盖德勒 先生
I'm George Gardelo, sir.
我们单独呆会好吗 乔治？
Would you excuse us, George?
- 当然  - 只要一会儿
- Yes. Of course. - Just for a second.
你怎么回事？
What's going on?
事情就是这个样子
That's how it happens.
小家伙用针线击败了一个帝国
A little guy with a needle and thread brings down an empire.
你真相信？
You really believe that?
形式无所谓
Look, it doesn't matter.
真谛是千里之堤毁于蚁穴嘛
If you let no one in, you get burned by no one.
知道毕加索的名言吗？
You know what Picasso said?
“好的艺术家复制”
"A good artist copies."
“伟大的艺术家偷窃”
"A great artist steals."
世界上没有什么东西是原创的 亚当
There's nothing original left in the world, Adam.
我们都是在偷窃
We're all stealing from someone.
你应该牢记这一点
You might want to remember that.
如果我损失1%的市场占有率
If I lose one percent market share,
只要1%我就毁了
one percent, and I'm ruined.
所谓的荷兰人生意
There is the Dutch deal,
但他们的开价只有艾康公司的一半
but they're offering half of what Eikon's willing to pay you.
不 我不介意
No, no, I don't care.
我宁可卖给荷兰人
I would rather counter the Dutch for a fraction
而不是戈达
than sell to Goddard.
卖给谁都比卖给艾康公司好
Anything's better than Eikon.
懂了
I know.
喂
Hello?
几时能帮我朋友们找到工作？
When are you going to find my friends jobs?
你一成功即可
As soon as you get me what I need.
你只有一次机会
You only have one shot at this.
将军
Mate.
汤姆伦格朗是艾康公司执行人事经理
Tom Lungren is executive hiring coordinator for Eikon.
你的目标是建立关系
Your objective here is to connect.
亚当？
Adam?
- 汤姆  - 汤姆伦格朗
- Tom. - Tom Lungren.
幸会 这位是艾玛詹宁斯
Nice to meet you. Let me introduce Emma Jennings,
我们的市场部经理
head of our marketing department.
幸会 艾玛
Nice to meet you, Emma.
请坐
Please, sit down.
我们还是从你那个…
Well, let me start off by saying that we're
Ethion 3.0展开话题吧
huge fans of the work you did on Ethion 3.0.
此项产品目前还没投入市场
Well, you know, it hasn't been released yet, so.
是因为电源管理部分还没有实现吗？
Is that because power management doesn't deliver?
不 电源管理没问题
No, the power management is fine.
这可与传闻不一样
That's not what we've heard.
我们正在调试网络模块
We're tweaking the networking module to make
以便达到市面上最快的下载速度
download speed the fastest on the market.
上帝 希望这不是我们找他的原因
Oh, God. I hope that's not why we agreed to meet with him.
你能说说配置吗？
Can you talk specs?
Orion采用LTE-A手机4G技术
The Orion was an LTE Advanced
最大速率为44.2mbps
with max speeds of 44.2 mbps.
我们新平台则是WAVE OS 7.5…
Our new platform is a WAVE OS 7.5...
该版本可能尚未解决7.0版本中的致命缺陷
Which probably won't solve the biggest issues you had with 7.0.
而我们的销量是你们的两倍
It outsold your model two to one.
是啊 市场是王道
Yeah, the marketing was genius.
我一手策划的活动
I spearheaded that campaign.
因为你非常善于隐藏缺陷
Then you know you're good at hiding flaws.
你俩认识？
Have you two met?
没有
No.
不
看来大家都出师不利
I think we got off on the wrong foot.
事前做好功课 这是你说的吧
Always do your homework. That's what you said, isn't it?
下次坚持我自己的意见吧
Next time follow your own advice.
- 难道不是汤姆·伦格朗？  - 是不光汤姆·伦格朗
- It wasn't Tom Lungren? - It wasn't just Tom Lungren.
我说过他可能带其它人来
I told you he might bring someone else.
带来的人我认识
Someone that I knew?
发生什么事？
What happened?
我用了一整天建立关系 漫天报价
I saved the day. Connected. Pulled an offer, a big-ass offer.
带你去新公寓吧
Let's take you to your new apartment.
- 什么公寓？  - 到时候你就知道了
- What apartment? - You'll see.
希望你喜欢
Thought you'd like it.
这是我的？
This is mine?
当然
Of course.
艾康公司的新经理看上去要像个有钱人
Eikon's newest executive needs to look the part.
很高兴再见到你 亚当
It's nice to see you again, Adam.
按照约定
Per our agreement,
我们已将50万元打入了中介账户
we've deposited $500,000 into an escrow account.
据悉 戈达两个月内可能会在奥罗拉发布新品
We're hearing Goddard could debut Aurora in the next two months,
我下载了你所有新同事的背景资料
so I've downloaded background files on all your co-workers.
首先是艾玛詹宁斯
First, Emma Jennings.
其父乔治詹宁斯曾是…
Father, George Jennings, was
纽约长老会医院的外科主任
Chief of Surgery at New York Presbyterian.
她共有四个兄弟
She grew up with four brothers,
曾经在男子俱乐部外面寻找机会
was always on the outside of the boys club, looking in.
拼命地想在男人世界中获得一席之地
Desperately wants to succeed in a man's world,
她是群体内准备最充分的人
so she's always the most prepared person in the room.
早几个小时前的话 这些信息很有用
Would have been useful a couple of hours ago.
别浪费时间 她有择偶标准的
Don't waste your time. She has certain standards.
朱迪斯 或许你并没有想象的那么聪明
Judith, maybe you're not as smart as you think you are.
现在别再交流内心了
Now don't always say what you think, darling.
因为从现在开始
Because from here on out,
你是地下工作者
you are all the way under.
我们只能通过这部手机联络
We'll be communicating through this phone only.
无论早晚 你必须回复我的电话
You will respond to my calls, no matter the time, day or night.
明白
You got it.
早上好 先生
Good morning, sir.
把他的体征扫描报告复印件送到我办公室
I want a copy of his body scan sent to my office.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
- 亚当  - 伦格朗先生
- Adam. - Mr. Lungren.
我说过了 你别那样叫我
I told you. You gotta stop calling me that,
让我感觉自己很老
you're gonna make me feel old.
- 欢迎来到艾康公司  - 谢谢 这里太棒了
- Welcome to Eikon. - Thank you. It's great to be here.
- 我们很庆幸你能来  - 谢谢
- We're damn glad to have you. - OK, good.
下几层是人事部
The lower floors are Legal, HR,
中层有一些其它部门 包括市场部
middle floors are all the other departments, including marketing.
38楼是最高安全机密的研发中心
The 38th floor is R&D, top security projects.
40楼到了
And we're here on the 40th.
这楼里有些规矩
There's just a few tricks to being in this building and getting around.
你按在钥匙卡上的指纹会生成密码
Your thumbprint on a keycard app generates a bar code
是你进入门禁系统的许可证
that gets you anywhere your clearance is allowed.
好的
All right.
聪慧的戈达有什么标语吗？
So any words of wisdom on Goddard?
卓越加诚恳
Be brilliant and be genuine.
他几英里外就能嗅到骗子
你的办公室
He can spot a fraud a mile away. Here's your office.
X型可用于社交网络
So, Type X was meant for social networking,
但事实证明人们并不总需要朋友
but it turns out that people don't always want their friends
准确的知道对方的方位
to know where they are so precisely.
没错 用的什么系统技术？
Right. What's the system tech?
3DPS 类似高精度GPS三角度量法
It's 3DPS, which is like GPS plus precise triangulation.
我对那个很熟悉
I'm familiar with it.
问题是两倍的重量造成电池消耗快三倍
Problem is, it's twice as heavy with three times the battery drain.
你算是给我出难题咯？
So, you're handing me a dead fish.
你有72小时 然后报告戈达
You've got 72 hours before you present to Goddard.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是一个实时跟踪装置 可以用于新用途
It's a real-time tracking device that needs a new purpose.
初次见面必须给他留下极深的印象
It's all about the presentation. You have to impress him.
我明白我该怎么做
Yes, I understand what I have to do.
我计划和研发中心的伙计们来一次头脑风暴
I'll schedule a brainstorming session with our best R&D guys.
你为啥干这份工作 朱迪斯？
Why do you do this work, Judith?
为忠诚还是为了钱？
I mean, is it out of loyalty, or is it just money?
你还有心考虑别人的事？
Don't you have enough to think about?
罗伊娜 召集所有…
Rowena, I need you to put together
研发小组成员
an R&D focus group.
我不管 叫醒他们
I don't care, wake them up.
准备好了通知我 再见
Call me when everything's in place. Bye.
士兵
Soldiers.
士兵们需要时刻知道对方在哪里
Soldiers need to know where each other are at all times.
- 他们有GPS  - 是的
- They have GPS. - Yeah.
GPS 适合导航 但在室内毫无用处
GPS is great for navigation, but it doesn't work indoors.
不能确定你是在一楼还是在九楼
Can't tell if you're on the first floor or the ninth,
所以在城市战中毫无用途
so it's useless in urban warfare.
但是3DPS
But with 3DPS,
如果我向所有人的电邮进行木马追踪…
if I can Trojan-horse tracking data in an e-mail to each of them...
…这事情兴许能成
...I could make this thing work.
- 你打给谁？  - 我自己的研发团队
- Who are you calling? - My own R&D focus group.
凯文 是我 我需要你帮忙
Yo, Kev, it's me. I need your help.
我被几家公司相中
I got recruited by one of those...
…猎头公司
...headhunters.
长话短说
Long story short,
我现在在艾康公司
I work for Eikon now.
听说他们不招人
I heard they weren't hiring.
我猜我走运吧
I got lucky, I guess.
我想也是
I guess.
我现在干的一个项目
Well, hey, I've been working on what we talked about,
绝对在军事上有用武之地
and the military thing is definitely possible.
我修改了一下艾康公司的软件
I just tweaked the Eikon software a little.
我称之为飞去来器
I'm calling it the Boomerang.
请看演示
Just check this out.
我把你的3DPS数据电邮给你
I sent your 3DPS data e-mail to you,
我还有艾莉森
me and Allison.
现在我们的手机并网了
So now our phones track each other working in unison.
你说的对 3DPS
And you were right, the SDPS,
是划时代的技术
that's what makes the difference.
你找我就找对人了
That was a good call, by the way.
伙计太棒了 干的好
Dude, that's awesome. You crushed this. Good job.
还没完
Yeah, but that ain't all.
接入艾莉森
Pick up Allison.
- 你要什么？  - 再一杯橙汁
- What can I get you? - Another OJ.
再一杯橙汁
One more OJ.
你是怎么做到的？
How the hell did you do that?
谁点的橙汁？
Who orders orange juice in a bar?
看来有人想要保持神秘感
Someone who wants to keep his edge.
- 你叫什么名字？  - 艾莉森
- What's your name? - Allison.
你认识那个人吗？
Do you know that guy?
橙汁先生！
Hey, OJ!
我们是一起睡的 我和她
We're sleeping together, me and her.
很高兴认识你 艾莉森
Nice to meet you, Allison.
我就只能坐在这里
All I do is sit around here,
不停的看人勾引她
watching her get hit on all the time.
累死我了！
It's exhausting!
我需要工作
I need a job.
早晨好 卡罗琳
让一下
Good morning, Caroline. Excuse me.
- 乔克·戈达  - 亚当·坎西迪
- Jock Goddard. - Adam Cassidy.
原来就是你啊 一切都还行？
Of course you are. Everything all right?
安顿得如何？
Settling in OK?
- 谢谢  - 办公室怎么样？
- Yeah. Thank you. - How's your office?
很漂亮 谢谢
Oh, yeah, it's beautiful. Thank you.
很好 我们开始吧
- Good. Let's get started.
好的
OK.
先生 我认为你把X型用于…
Well, sir, I'm afraid you've wasted a lot of money
开发社交网络设备是个浪费行为
developing Type X as a social networking device.
因为此设备在军事方面相当有前景
But the military applications of this device are undeniable.
早上我给所有人发了邮件
I sent you all an e-mail this morning
内含类3DPS身份鉴别数据
in which I encoded 3DPS-like data to identify you.
会议室里所有人都收到了电邮
Everyone I sent an e-mail to is in this room.
除了一人
Except for one.
现代战争还是无法避免被友方误伤
Death by friendly fire remains a sad reality of war.
而3DPS比GPS更精确 并含海拔高度数据
3DPS is more precise than GPS and works on a Z-axis.
虽然对普通人来说这个产品太重
While the product was deemed too heavy for civilians,
不过多12盎司对于士兵来说不算什么
an added 12 ounces is nothing to a soldier.
这就是你对于我们手机项目的完整分析？
So this is all so you can see what floor our phones are on?
是的 战争进入白热化状态时
Yes. 'Cause in the heat of battle
它会有不俗的表现
that can be the difference
命悬杀死敌人或者…
between killing the enemy or...
…被敌人杀死的一线间
...killing your own.
X型则刚好挽救了她的生命
Type X just saved her life.
早
Good morning.
早 对不起
Good morning, sorry.
早
Morning.
你用了多久研究结论？
How long have you had with this?
72小时 先生
Seventy-two hours, sir.
为亚当组建一个团队
Let's put together a team for Adam.
设计工程部
Design, engineering.
打探下能否得到国防部资助
Let's see if we can get some DOD funding.
有问题吗？ 没有？ 很好
Issues? No? Good.
很好
Good.
- 棒极了  - 好
- Nice work. - OK.
一切进展顺利
I thought that went pretty well.
新手的好运
Beginner's luck.
想取悦你还真不容易
You are hard to please.
与你预料的有差距
Not that you'd remember.
这周末我们一起晚餐吧
Let me take you to dinner this weekend.
这周末我必须去汉普顿
I have to be in the Hamptons this weekend.
好啊 我和你一起去
Oh, good. I'll come with you.
这可不是邀请
It wasn't an invitation.
好的
OK.
你好 亚当 我是乔克·戈达的助理
Hi, Adam. I'm calling from Jock Goddard's office.
乔克先生邀请部分客人光临他在汉普顿的家
Jock is having a few people over to his house in the Hamptons
时间是星期六 他希望你也来
on Saturday and he'd like you to join him.
目前已申请军方资助了
So now we go for military funding.
好极了 祝贺你
Dude, that's great. Congratulations, man.
我有一事相求
Hey, so, I got a favor to ask.
我下周要到艾康公司面试
I got an interview at Eikon next week.
也许我的简历会成为故纸推中的一张
And I know I'm gonna be another resume in a stack
除非我有闪光点
if I don't build some traction.
对
Right.
很难为情 不过…
So, I feel awkward even asking you this, but...
别担心
Hey, of course.
周一我会和人事部打招呼的
All right, I'll speak to HR on Monday.
放心吧
All right.
多谢
Thanks.
那家伙人还不错
Nicest guy.
闯红灯追尾我的车
Right through the red light and hit the back of the car.
- 诚恳的道歉  - 有人破财了
- Very apologetic. - Somebody looks lost.
- 他来了  - 很高兴你能来
- There he is. - I'm glad you could make it.
- 谢谢你的邀请 戈达先生  - 叫我乔克
- Thanks for having me, Mr. Goddard. - Jock.
你认识汤姆的 对吧
You know Tom, of course.
乔克告诉我说股票升值了
Jock tells me my stock's gone up in value
因为你对X型的定位
since your Type X pitch.
上场第一击就爆掉了计分牌
First time up at bat and you bang it off the scoreboard?
就该这么干
Way to go.
这是艾玛 负责我们的…
And this is Emma. She's spearheading the marketing
新Occura智能手机市场工作
on our new smartphone, Occura.
西装不错
Nice suit.
别小看她
Watch our for her.
她可是普林斯顿常青藤大学的高材生哟
She's one of those Ivy Leaguers. Princeton.
应该是耶鲁大学吧？
Yale, actually.
她兄弟们也念耶鲁大学
Where her brothers went.
你怎么知道我是耶鲁的？
How did you know I went to Yale?
脸书或是别的地方听说的
It was on Facebook or something.
毫无隐私啊
So much for privacy.
隐私 现在已经是种笑话了
Privacy. Absolute myth, no such thing.
- 汤姆 想喝一杯吗？  - 当然
- Tom, you want a drink? - Yeah, absolutely.
白葡萄酒 先生？
A glass of wine, sir?
- 白葡萄酒  - 我要冰矿泉水
- White wine. - Mineral water, cold.
待会见
See you later.
有点像波尔多 太干了
Kind of like a Bordeaux, more dry.
如果你在找卫生间 走过头了
if you're looking for the bathroom, you missed it.
不好意思 …
Yeah, sorry, I, uh...
我看到那个收音机  还能用吗？
I saw the radio. Does it work?
还能用 全都能用 我做的
Yeah, they work. They all work. I built them.
十多岁时的癖好 火腿一族(业余无线电)
That's how I spent my teens. Ham radio.
你在哪儿长大？
Where'd you grow up?
汉米尔顿 人口约3500人
Town of Hamilton, 3500 people.
那是哪里？
Where is that?
不值一提
It doesn't matter.
你让我想起怀特公司
You remind me of Wyatt.
非常吃惊他们居然放你走
I'm surprised he let you go.
他对我不甚感兴趣
He wasn't too happy about it.
我知道有一天他们会成为我的强力竞争对手
I knew he'd be my competition someday.
我在他意识到之前就意识到了
I knew it before he did.
那你为什么把他收入麾下？
Why'd you take him under your wing?
与他个人无关 事关开发产品…
It's not about him. It's about putting products out there
能让人们生活的更好
to make people's lives better.
竞争推动创新
Competition fuels innovation.
否则就没有艾康公司的今天
Without it, Eikon wouldn't be where it is today.
现在发展到什么阶段了？
And where is that?
革命前夜
On the eve of a revolution.
你儿子吗？
Is that your son?
是的 迪兰
Yeah, that's Dylan.
人一旦有点成功 就会觉得自己…
You have a bit of success, you begin to think
能左右一些事情 但…
that you've got some control over things, but...
…天往往不遂人愿
...shit happens to everybody.
是啊
Yeah.
我7岁时丧母
I lost my mother when I was seven.
你还记得她吗？
Do you remember her?
不太记得了
Not much.
我感觉她逐渐离我远去
I feel like I lose her a little more every day.
对
Yeah.
迪兰死后的很多夜晚
Couple nights after Dilly died,
我常在夜晚痛醒
I woke up in the middle of the night in a panic.
翻遍整个房子 他的整个房间…
Rummaged through the whole house, his whole room...
…试图找到一点慰籍
...looking for anything.
孩提的涂鸦画 作业本…
Kid's drawings, schoolwork...
…旧网球鞋
...old pair of tennis shoes.
一切能回忆起他的东西
Anything that would keep him alive.
在前厅楼梯口
The front hall, under the stairs.
什么先生？
Sir?
卫生间
The bathroom.
谢谢
Thanks.
（米彻姆：继续等待）
你的西装也没那么差劲啦
You know, the suit's not all that bad.
你不用藏在这里
You don't have to hide way out here.
我这是欲擒故纵
I was, uh, playing hard to get.
显然你得手了
But you're already gotten.
告诉我
So tell me,
你怎么会了解我那么多事
how is it that you know so much about me
而我却对你一无所知？
and I know nothing about you?
我祖母住的是一个小房间
It's this, uh, little row home my grandmother owned.
五个人共用洗手间
Five of us sharing one bathroom.
我爸爸曾是保安
My dad was a security guard.
现在患有肺气肿 但还在吸烟
Now he has emphysema, but still smokes.
我敢肯定他把烟藏在护士那儿
And I'm pretty sure he's putting it to the nurse I'm paying for.
每当我想到要失去他…
When I think of losing him...
你呢？
What about you?
我家教严格…
I come from a family where...
家里期望过高
the expectation is so high
我真的难以达成
that I can't really ever succeed.
好在我一直有努力
It's fine, it's just that I keep trying.
那么…
So...
我想一路睡到高层
I'm trying to sleep my way to the top.
地下恋情么？
Are we covered?
得了 带我回家？
Come on. Take me home?
好
Yeah.
爸爸？
Dad?
有客人来
You got a visitor.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你应该扣掉手机电池
You might want to remove the battery from your cellular device.
什么？
What?
别以为你没在通话状态
You think 'cause you're not on a call,
他们就听不到你
they can't hear you?
探员甘布
Agent Gamble.
FBI犯罪调查科
I'm with the FBI's Criminal Investigation Division.
我们调查怀特公司有五年了
We've been looking at the Wyatt Corp for about five years now.
- 我不在怀特公司工作  - 约翰·摩尔是怀特员工
- I don't work for Wyatt. - John Moore did.
他09年就参与了怀特公司的培训程序
He was in Wyatt's training program in '09.
史黛·拉罗斯
Stella Ross,
像你一样从怀特跳槽到艾康公司
migrated from Wyatt to Eikon like you.
两个月后死于汽车的转向柱爆炸
Two months later, her steering column exploded.
理查德·麦卡利斯特…
And Richard McAllister...
你剽窃过他的Ethion方案
whose Ethion work you drafted off of.
我没有剽窃他的工作
I didn't draft off his work.
一个月前 你还在怀特闲晃
A month ago, you were circling the drain at Wyatt.
现在你却是艾康公司的座上宾？
Now you're some hotshot exec over at Eikon?
别扯蛋了
Don't bullshit me.
好的 我想你可以走了
OK, I think it's time for you to go.
你以为怀特会给你一大笔钱然后让你安然离开？
You think Wyatt's gonna fill your pockets and let you walk?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about, OK?
别这样 亚当
Come on, Adam.
你以为你还能挺多久？
How long do you think you can keep this up?
只要一个过失 你立马就玩完
All it takes is one mistake, one slip up.
对不起 我帮不了你
I'm sorry, I can't help you.
别追悔莫及
Just don't wait till it's too late.
你不打算告诉我发生什么事了吗？
You wanna tell me what's going on?
你不懂的
You wouldn't understand.
我以前太匆忙
Yeah, I was probably too busy
每天供你三餐
putting three meals in front of you every day
给你别人都有的父母之爱
and giving you all the love that parents had.
亚当 我们会过得幸福的
Come on, Adam. We had a perfect life.
如果花在你身上的保险有一半能用在妈妈…
You know, if your insurance covered even half of what morn needed...
别和病魔斗争
Don't try to revise death.
不然你希望我怎么样？
What did you want me to do?
我希望你斗争
I wanted you to fight.
我想我们至少能给妈一次机会
I wanted us to have enough to at least give her a chance.
但你却放弃了
You gotta give that up.
这些公司把财富都偷走了
These companies steal so much,
不剩一点
there's nothing left to earn.
你的所为也没有什么成效
Yeah, what you're doing doesn't make it right.
没有
No.
没有人能绝对正确
No one can make it right.
我为什么不能得到属于自己的一份？
So, why shouldn't I get my share? Huh?
FBI刚从我们家离开
The FBI just walked out of our house.
我不想跟你一样的人生
I don't want to end up like you.
原来乔克是这个想法
So that's what he's up to.
你要的都齐了
That's what you wanted.
任务完成 卑鄙的我
I'm done now. This isn't who I am.
你本性如此 搜过他身没有？
This is exactly who you are. Did you frisk him?
你有所隐藏？
You hiding something?
住手！
Knock it Off!
你最近内心有点波澜吧？
You've been a little temperamental lately, haven't you?
你爱上那女人了？
Are you falling for that girl?
- 他爱上的是乔克  - 好了 好了！
- He's falling for Jock. - All right, all right!
他说什么了？
What'd he talk about?
他谈到科技进步 丰富了人们的生活
He talked about progress, enriching people's lives.
谈到他儿子了吗？
Yeah, he talk about his son?
说了一点
Yeah. A little.
是不是很耳熟？
It seem rehearsed?
不
No.
我早就说了
It did the first time he told it.
当全世界都爱上乔克·戈达的时候
That was when the world fell in love with Jock Goddard,
痛不欲生的父亲
the grieving father.
幸好因为他儿子的噩耗拯救了艾康公司
That story of his little dead boy saved Eikon.
我已经拿到你想要的 懂吗？
I got what you asked for, OK?
我们有约在先 我只想拿到我的钱
We had a deal. I just want my money.
他想拿份内钱
Oh, he wants his money.
钱我们暂时替你保管
We'll keep your money for you.
你还得更进一步
You'll be doing five to ten upstate.
我已经按约定拿到了规格书 说好的
I got the specs. That was the deal.
光有图片还不够好
Pictures are no good to me.
我需要知道是什么情况
I need to know what it does,
我想要的是把它拿在手里 看实际运行效果！
I need to hold it in my hand and see it run!
听懂了没有 必须拿到我手里！
Do you understand me? Put it in my fucking hand!
不然怎样？ 像理查德一样被终结？
Or what? I end up like Richard?
乔克负责建立原型体
Jock builds one prototype.
各部件的组装都在研发中心密室进行
It's assembled in the vault, piece by piece,
直到验收测试
until beta trials.
这间密室位于第38层
It stays in the vault on the 38th floor.
没有文件 没有源码 你什么也…
Without files, without source code, you can't do...
不 我不需要他的文件
No, I don't need his files.
我只需看到他的思想原型
I just need to see his vision.
不 我不干了
No, I'm not doing this anymore.
我退出
I'm out.
你退出？ 孩子 等我说你可以退出的时候
You're out? You are only out, my son,
你才能退出
when I say you're out!
你现在受我胁迫
I own you right now.
明白吗？一切尽在我的掌握
You see? I can get to anyone.
别把事情复杂化
Don't make this harder than it has to be.
生意就是生意 亚当
It's just business, Adam.
每个人都偷窃 每个人都说谎
Everybody steals, everybody lies.
无所谓对错
There's no right or wrong.
只有输和赢
There's just winning or losing.
现在第一步任务
Now the first order of business
是提取艾玛的指纹
is lifting Emma's fingerprints.
我父母最近忙着操办…
So my parents are having this thing
我哥在周末的婚礼
for my brother's engagement this weekend.
要我一起去吗？
You wanna go with me?
拜见父母？
To meet your parents?
吃顿饭而已
It's just dinner and drinks.
你们…
You, uh...
你确定可以和我发展长久关系了？
You sure I'm relationship material?
算了 一起吃饭也挺无聊的
You know what? It's... It's actually gonna be really boring.
你不去也好
Probably better if you don't.
我当然去
Of course I will.
无聊也去？
Even if it is boring?
是 无聊也去
Yeah, even if it's boring.
怎么了你？
Hey, what happened to you?
凯文 你怎么来了？
Kev! What are you doing here?
你以为我在做什么？
What do you think I'm doing here?
对 面试
Your interview. Right.
- 情况如何？ 我和人事部门招呼过了  - 不 你没有
- How'd it go? I spoke to HR. - No, you didn't.
对不起 兄弟 我…
I'm sorry, man. I, uh...
我最近压力很大
I've been under a ton of pressure.
完全忘了…
I completely forgot...
是啊 我理解你
Yeah, I understand, man.
你去了新公司 买新车 有新女朋友
Your new apartment, new car, new girlfriend.
你真不知道我的处境
You have no idea what I'm dealing with.
是 我不知道 这辈子也无法知道了
No, I don't. And I don't think I ever will.
- 谢谢  - 凯文 我真的很抱歉
- Thanks. - Come on, Kev. I'm sorry, man.
凯文！
Kev!
戈达先生想见你
Mr. Goddard wants to see you.
好 我知道的
Yeah, I understand that.
怀特公司必须考虑我方的提议
Wyatt has to consider our offer.
他没的选
He has no choice.
我指的是 他现在像是在泰坦尼克号上跳舞
(马上要完蛋)
I mean, he's tap dancing on the Titanic.
进来吧
Come on in.
有人进来了而已
Look, somebody just walked in.
我有些事务要处理下
I've got something I've got to deal with.
好吧 谢谢
All right. Thanks.
别忘记您在俱乐部预订的午餐
Don't forget, you have a lunch reservation at the club.
我们去兜兜风 顺便请你吃午饭
Come on. Let's take a drive. I'll buy you lunch.
今早收到一些与你有关的新闻
Got some interesting news this morning concerning you.
说给你听之前 我得确认真假
Thought I'd make sure it was true before I talk to you about it.
- 一切还好吧？  - 你说呢
- Is everything all right? - You tell me.
国防部同意投资X型了
The DOD has given us preliminary funding for Type X.
- 就停这里吧 戈达先生  - 谢了 伙计
- We'll leave it here, Mr. Goddard. - Thanks, Bud.
- 觉得怎样？  - 充满了力量
- Well, what do you think? - It's powerful.
没错
Yeah, it is.
算是你拯救X型项目的红利吧
Consider it a loaner for saving Type X.
- 乔克 我不能接受  - 你可以
- Jock, I couldn't. - Yeah, you could.
力量就像果汁 你得习惯饮用它
Power is the juice, get used to drinking it.
我听你谈到Occura
I heard you talking about Occura.
外面有很多疯传
There's a lot of buzz about it.
是的 Occura项目已经待产
Yeah, Occura's been, uh, gestating
这些年来
for... quite a few years.
直到最近我们才能…
We only recently were able to put
把所有的元素组装成实用版本
all of the elements together to make it happen.
- 一杯咖啡  - 一杯水
- I'll have coffee. - I'll have a water.
好的
Very good.
想象外出时除了手机什么都不带
Imagine walking around with nothing but your cell phone.
没有钱包 没有钥匙
No wallet, no keys.
手机可以是数字钱包
Like a digital wallet.
是驾照 是信用卡
It'll be your driver's license, it'll be your credit card,
是很多其它东西
it'll be more than that.
超薄可折叠
Super slim. Foldable,
能自充电
with a battery that recharges itself
只要附近有环境电源
from any ambient electrical source.
它知道你去过哪里 和谁去的
It'll know where you've been, who you've been with.
它能帮你处理轻重缓急 理财
It'll track your priorities, expenditures,
监管身体 日程安排
your health, calendar.
它知道你的全部
It will know who you are.
而它则受我们的控制
And it's all ours.
你真的认为同处一室的人…
You think people really want all that personal information
也会要这样的私人信息？
under one roof?
与同处一室无关 亚当
It's not the roof that matters, Adam.
它提供的是一种家的温暖感觉
It's the warm fuzzy feeling of the home under it.
现在的人都神经兮兮的
People are so distracted these days,
经常连自己是谁都忘了
they don't know who they are.
但我们不会
But we will.
我们甚至比他们自己更了解他们
We'll know them better than they know themselves.
天啊
Oh, my goodness.
乔克
Jock.
尼克
Nick.
多久没见了？
How long has it been?
没多久
Not long enough.
你还是一副一柱擎天的气势
You look like you're holding up all right.
喔 还行 哪阵风把你吹到这儿来的？
Oh, I'm doing fine. What brings you here?
午饭风 午饭风驱使我来的
Lunch. Lunch brings me here.
- 你还记得朱迪斯吗  - 当然
- You remember Judith. - Oh, of course.
- 你好 朱迪斯？  - 还行
- How are you, Judith? - Good.
记得亚当·坎西迪吗？
You remember Adam Cassidy.
是他设计了你的Ethion
He designed your Ethion.
当然是他
Yes, he did.
你也好 亚当
Hello, again, Adam.
他让我想起了你
He reminds me of you.
回想当年 你抛弃了我们
Way back when, before you walked out on us.
别颠倒黑白吧
Let's not muddle the facts.
是你赶我走 然后关上我身后的门
You asked me to walk and locked the door behind me.
好在我比亚当聪明点
Besides, I was smarter than Adam here.
我没有浪费时间去拍你的马屁
And I didn't spend all my time kissing your ass.
Ethion项目进展如何？
How is Ethion?
我们有些耳闻
We've heard remarkably little about it.
Ethion项目进展顺利
Ethion's fine.
Occura项目如何？
How's Occura?
计划之中
Right on schedule.
有一点你永远无法复制
And it's something you're never going to be able to duplicate.
是什么？
Is that so?
尼克 记得我们曾经共同创意？
Remember when we used to share ideas, Nick?
我没忘
I try not to.
我俩一起时
When we put our heads together,
没有我们解决不了的问题
there was no problem we couldn't solve.
没有什么我们做不出来的
Nothing we couldn't make.
应该是没什么我解决不了的困难
There was no problem I couldn't solve.
没什么我做不出来的东西
Nothing I couldn't make.
我怀念你的友谊
I miss your friendship.
不如我们什么时候再聚聚
Why don't we sit down together sometime.
你总是满嘴胡言 你坐着就像…
Always so full of shit. You sit here like...
…像个令人仰慕的大亨
...like some big shot with boy wonder here,
用屁股吞云吐雾 搞的煞有介事
blowing smoke up your ass like it's still relevant.
事实是我会埋葬了你
The truth is, I'm gonna bury you,
替你工作的人将会替我工作
and your boy here is gonna be working for me again.
因为替你工作就是替我工作
Because working for you, means he'll be working for me.
别让午餐变冷 尼克
Don't let your lunch get cold, Nick.
很高兴见到你 朱迪斯
Nice seeing you, Judith.
他一遍一遍的查戈达的资料
He's running search after search on Goddard.
他在找什么？
What is he looking for?
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得这孩子已经开始动摇了
I think this boy's gone soft on us.
你不接我的电话？
Were you going to ignore my call?
你应该告诉我怀特也会去
You should have told me Wyatt was gonna be there.
你为什么来回的踱步 看上去很紧张
Why do you keep pacing so much? You look nervous.
有什么要说的吗？
You have something you want to tell me?
你在哪？
Where are you?
现在我来解释下一步行动
Now let me explain to you how this is going to work.
我们拿你一个朋友开刀
We hit one of your friends first.
可能是个女性
Or maybe the girl.
如果你敢动她…
If you even touch her...
那就去拿到我们所要的东西
Then get us what we need.
给你两天时间入侵艾康公司
You have two days to break into Eikon.
最后一次警告
This is your last warning.
帮帮我！快来帮帮我
Help! Help me! Somebody help me!
他说我有两天时间 前晚说的
He said I had two days. That was the night before last.
这些人无孔不入
These people are everywhere.
在你家中布满摄像头
Put cameras in your house.
对不起 我只是…
I'm sorry. I just...
我搞砸了 爸爸
I messed up, Dad.
我本以为知道自己在干什么
I thought I knew what I was doing.
你必须自谋生路
You have to figure a way out.
亚当
Adam.
- 亚当！  - 是真的 好吗？
- Adam! - This is serious, OK?
你必须自谋生路
You got to figure a way out.
没那么容易
It's not that easy.
好吗？关心我的人都处于危险之中
OK? I put a lot of people I care about in danger.
亚当 我觉得FBI是唯一的选择
Adam, I think the FBI is the only option.
我会坐牢的
I could go to jail.
不然他们会杀了你
Or they could kill you.
一辆黑车突然窜出来撞倒了他
There was a black car and it just came out of nowhere and it hit him.
慢点 他还好吗？
你在哪儿？
Slow down. Is he all right? Where are you?
我联系了你一整天
I've been trying to reach you all day.
凯文在医院 他还好
Kev's at the hospital, but he's OK.
我猜他们在威胁我们
I think they're discharging us now.
有目击证人吗？有没有看到牌照？
OK, were there witnesses? Did anyone get the plates?
不清楚 不知道
I don't think so. I don't know,
一切来得太快 我得走了
it just all happened so fast. I got to go.
- 记得再电话我  - 我会的
- OK, call me back. - I will.
你什么毛病？！
Hey! What's the matter with you?!
闪开！
Go, go, go, go!
跪下
On your knees.
- 我照做！  - 快跪下！
- I'll do it, I'll do it! - Get on your knees!
你今晚溜进去
You're going in tonight,
你会用到艾玛的手机
and you'll need Emma's phone to do it.
起来干活
Get moving.
我能进来吗？
Can I come in?
我对你不诚实
I haven't been honest with you.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
有些事我没有告诉你
There's things I want to tell you that I haven't told you.
关于什么？
What is it?
坎西迪先生
Mr. Cassidy.
- 怎么  - 这么晚加班？
- Yeah? - Working late tonight?
熬夜燃烧脂肪
Burning that midnight oil.
亚当？
Adam?
（系统关闭）
一到第五层都断电了
I've lost floors one through five.
我们已打开第二区安全灯
We've got security lights in sector two.
坚守岗位
Hold your position.
接通网络管理员的电话
Get our IT guy on the line.
去第三区前
Before we move on to sector three,
检查一下服务器
let's check that server.
我要大楼内所有人的名单
I want the list of everyone in the building.
别动…
Control...
- 只有一笔进出记录  - 是谁？
- I'm only showing one exec present. - Who is it?
亚当·坎西迪
Adam Cassidy.
拜托
Oh, come on.
我是艾玛 请留言
Hi, it's Emma. Leave a message.
马丁 去查一下亚当·坎西迪
Marty, go check on Adam Cassidy.
收到 我去了！
Roger, I'm en route. Come on!
（无法验证）
（第2次 共3次）
亚当·坎西迪不在办公室
Adam Cassidy is not in his office.
妈的
Shit.
全员追缉 不惜一切手段
All hands on, get this guy! Use any means necessary.
安全
Clear.
坎西迪先生！
Mr. Cassidy!
有人在研发中心密室
We've got somebody at the vault.
（一日为贼 日日为贼）
搞什么？
What the hell?
乔克
Jock.
坎西迪先生
Mr. Cassidy.
人赃并获了吧？
Got caught with your hand in the cookie jar, didn't you?
我… 乔克 我可以解释这一切
I... Jock, I can explain this.
你打算从哪里开始？
Where you gonna start?
我真的没想到
I was beginning to think it would never happen.
怀特宁愿公司倒闭
Wyatt would rather watch his company crumble
也不肯卖给我
than sell it to me.
而你则带着野心一同搅局
Then you came along with your blind ambition.
我们录下了所有的会谈
We recorded it all, every conversation,
你和怀特的每条信息
every text between you and Wyatt.
你告诉尼克 让他把公司股份转卖给我
You tell Nick he'll be selling me majority shares in his company
否则我就把你们互相勾结的证据交给FBI
or evidence of your collusion goes to the FBI.
你操纵我
You manipulated me.
是的
Yes.
明天中午萨顿俱乐部
You'll be at the Sutton Club tomorrow at noon.
你 尼克 还有我
You, Nick, and me.
没有外人 不带律师 不带保镖
Nobody else. No lawyers, no handlers. Nobody.
让他走！
Let him out!
天大的错误
Big mistake.
是的
Yeah.
你怎么来了 你不能呆着
What are you doing here? You can't be here.
你利用我
You used me.
很抱歉
I'm sorry. OK? I'm so sorry.
你必须走 这里不安全
You got to go, you're not safe here.
每件事…你说的每句话
Everything you... everything you said,
你做的每件事…
every... everything you did...
都是撒谎
was a lie.
不 不全是
No, that's not true. Not everything.
我想出人头地
I wanted to be someone else.
你成功了
Now you are.
你知道…
You know...
我爱你是因为你的与众不同
I fell for you because you weren't like everyone else.
艾玛 我会弥补一切的
Emma, I'm gonna make this right.
你根本不了解局势
You don't know what that is.
你搞砸了
Well, you sure messed that up.
我还在想办法 好吗？
Hey, look, I'm trying, OK?
好了 你的办法完了 我们去兜风
Yeah, well, now you're done trying. Let's go for a ride.
- 你什么都没有得到吧？  - 都是设计好的陷阱！
- Look, you don't get it, OK? - It was all a setup!
- 上车！  - 这都是设计好的！
- Get in the car! - It was all a setup!
对不起 兄弟
I'm sorry, man.
道什么歉？
What are you sorry for?
又不是你的撞的我
You didn't run me over, did you?
都是我的错
I'm the reason for all of this.
问题是…
The real question is...
…接下来我们怎么办？
...what are we gonna do about it?
我会以牙还牙 我…
I'm going to use what they taught me...
…摧毁他们的帝国
...to destroy what they built.
和荷兰人交易进展如何？
So, what's the news on the Dutch deal?
- 不知道  - 他们已经没有价值了
- I don't know. - Good, we won't need them anyway.
记得没请你啊
Don't remember inviting you.
我的离职派对会为一切画上句话
My going-away party got this whole thing rolling.
这可能是我在你们面前最后一次露面
I thought it was only fair that I show up for yours.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
戈达策划了所有这一切…
Goddard orchestrated this whole thing...
…诱导你陷入犯罪泥沼
...to entrap you into committing a crime.
我没有犯罪
I didn't commit a crime.
是你做的
You did.
你的帝国就要毁灭了
This is the death of your empire, Nick.
给你的钱与我无关
And you were funded with money I never touched,
是一家我从未听过的公司经手的
by corporations I had never heard of.
那家公司一分不值
He has nothing.
你错了 他掌控一切
He has everything.
电邮 短信
E-mails, texts.
还破解了摄像头
He got the break-in on camera.
所有的线索都指向你
All the dots connect back to you.
整个事情都是设计好的
The whole thing was a setup.
怎么回事？怎么回事？
What's going on? What's going on?
我们自有周详！
We had good intel on this!
你何谈周详 尼克？
Where did you get that intel, Nick?
别荒谬了
This is absurd.
你不能…
You can't just...
汉米尔顿
Hamilton.
乔克的老家
Jack's hometown.
尼克…
Nick...
米彻姆
Meachum.
解决一个
That's one down.
还有一个
One more to go.
不管你用什么招 最好管用
Whatever you have better be good.
如果奏效 我们都撤退比较保险
If it works, we both walk away with an insurance policy
再多的钱都也买不来
no amount of money can buy.
万一不奏效呢？
Yeah, but if it doesn't?
拿出手机 请坐
Get out your phones. Sit down.
扣出电池放在桌上
Put the batteries on the table.
它说你有备机
It says you've got another phone.
- 不 不  - 怎么了？
- Oh, no, no. - What happened?
信号丢失 两部都没了
I lost the signal. Both phones, they're gone.
能找回来吗？
Can you get it back?
- 你必须出价  - 我会付钱的
- You'll pay for this. - Yeah, I'll pay.
我买下你怀特公司该死的全部股权
I'm buying every goddamn share of Wyatt Corporation's stock you own,
只需40%的钱
and I'm paying 40 cents on the dollar.
意下如何？
How does that sound?
即便我不收购你 联邦政府也会收购你
I get it or the Feds do.
- 你不会得逞的  - 闭嘴 亚当
- You'll never get away with this. - Shut up, Adam.
你不过是个方便的工具 绣花枕头
You're nothing but a convenient tool, an empty vessel.
我塞你一嘴屎尿
I filled you with piss and vinegar
告诉你这是香槟 你一样舔得干干净净
and told you it was champagne and you lapped it up.
- 我不会签字的  - 那你等着坐牢
- I'm not signing this. - Then you'll go to jail.
凭什么？ 你有什么王牌？！
With what? What have you got?!
什么？
What?
- 赶紧签！  - 你已经很得势了
- Sign it! - You have taken credit for everything.
你什么都没有创造过！
And you've created nothing!
你这个自大的混蛋！
You arrogant bastard!
我把一件被众人耻笑的砖头设备…
I took a brick device that everybody laughed at
最终变成人类寸步不离的宝贝
and turned it into the one thing that no one can do without.
我的自大是我自己挣来的！
I earned my arrogance!
是的！但没有我什么都不会发生
Yes, and none of that happens without me!
你是站在我肩膀上！
You stood on my shoulders!
现在我站在你的脖子上！
And now I'm standing on your neck!
我始终比你棋高一着 尼克
I'm 15 moves ahead of you, Nick.
荷兰人也给我报价了！
The Dutch offer, me!
我一直没能收紧圈套 直到…
I strung you along until the only hope was...
亚当的出现
Adam.
这不可能
That's impossible.
不可能？
Impossible?
我建立了怀特公司
I built Wyatt Corp.
卖不卖 你的公司都完蛋了
Sell or not, your company is finished.
你没有稻草绳可抓了 即便有
You've got nothing in the pipe, and even if you did,
你也没有资金投放市场
you've got no money to market it with.
40%的股份 总比坐牢好吧
Forty cents on the dollar is a lot better than jail.
你自行决定
You make the choice.
现在滚
Now get out.
他喜欢干掉自己的年轻一辈
He likes to eat his young.
那也是我的自由
They're mine to eat.
该回去过你原本的悲惨生活了
It's time to go back to your sad little life.
何必大费周章？
Why go to all the trouble?
因为我想看到他头破血流 你走吧
Because I wanted to see him bleed. Go.
不 远非如此
No. There's more to it,
你没必要出此险招的
you wouldn't risk it all just for that.
我说过 亚当
I told you, Adam,
竞争激发创新
competition breeds innovation.
他在公司混得有模有样后 私欲膨胀
With his name on the door, he developed his ass off.
你需要他
You needed him.
你需要他的创造力 因为他比你聪明
You needed his mind because he was smarter than you.
他把一片伟大的处理器用在一部屎样的手机上
He made a great processor and a shitty phone
他该落得和你一样的下场 走吧
and he served a purpose, just like you did. Go.
没有他你什么都干不了
You're nothing without him.
Occura是真的 我说到做到
Occura is real. It'll do everything I said it would.
我不过是需要他的处理器而已
I just needed his processor to run it.
- 谁？  - 戈达先生？
- Who is this? - Mr. Goddard?
是谁？
Who is this?
你真应该彻底删除你收到的电邮
You should really trash your e-mails when you're done reading them.
早上我给所有人发了邮件
I sent you all an e-mail this morning
内含类3DPS身份鉴别数据
in which I encoded 3DPS-like data to identify you.
有人一直在偷听 乔克
Someone is always listening, Jock.
一直
Always.
戈达先生
Mr. Goddard.
戈达先生 你被捕了
Mr. Goddard, you're under arrest.
我会让你生不如死
I'm gonna make your life a living hell.
站起来 手放背后
Please stand, place your hands behind your back.
我们逮到他了
Yes! We got him.
你们做了一件大好事儿 孩子
You did the right thing, kid.
现在指控你重罪欺诈
The charges against you include felony fraud,
商业间谍罪
industrial espionage,
妨碍司法
obstruction of justice,
及内幕交易
insider trading.
奥古斯丁·戈达 你有权保持沉默
Augustine Goddard, you have the right to remain silent.
但你所说的一切都将成为呈堂证供
Anything you say can and will be used in a court of law.
你有权请律师
You have the right to an attorney.
如果你请不起律师
If you cannot afford an attorney,
法院也会为你指派一名律师
the court will appoint one for you.
听懂我宣读的你的权利了？
Do you understand these rights as I have read them to you?
我向FBI举报了怀特和戈达
I handed the Feds Wyatt and Goddard.
他们将有段日子看不到阳光了
They won't be seeing light for a very long time.
朱迪斯和米彻姆罪有应得
Judith and Meachum got what they deserved too.
而我很幸运
As for me, I got lucky.
因为我的合作 所以联邦调查局放我一马
The Feds cut me a break for my cooperation.
不…
No...
曾经的追求现在想来其实也没那么重要
The things I thought I wanted don't seem so important anymore.
吃一堑长一智 还有…
I do know right from wrong, and...
…隔了这么久才能做回我自己
...I'm sorry it took me so long to act on it.
我只想你知道
I just want you to know that
我从不曾想对不起你
I never wanted to do any of this to you.
希望有一天我能弥补一切
I hope one day I can make things right.
对不起 艾玛
I'm sorry, Emma.
谢谢
Thanks.
快！快！快！快！
Go, go, go, go! Go! Go! Go!
快跑 快跑！
Run, run!
干嘛？
What?
我有说你是对的吗？
Did I ever tell you, you were right?
关于什么？
About what?
一切
Everything.
真心的
I mean that.
抱歉我以前没有听你的
I'm sorry I didn't listen to you.
和那女孩发展的怎么样了？
How's it going with that girl?
她不愿意和我说话
Well, she won't talk to me.
塞翁失马焉知非福
It ain't over till it's over.
知道我约你妈出来约了多久吗？
You know how long it took me to get a date with your mother?
多久？
How long?
花儿都谢了
A long time.
我那时比你现在还帅
And I was much better-looking then than you are now.
- 真的吗？  - 噢耶
- Oh, is that right? - Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
你去哪儿？地铁在这边
Where you going? The subway is this way.
我有更快的交通工具 过来
I got a faster ride. Come on.
我以为这事情已经了结了呢？
I thought we were done with this shit?
租的啦 老爸 我租了一天
It's a rental, Dad. I got it for the day.
哦 真的吗？好啦 让我们找点乐子去
Oh, yeah? Well, then, let's have some fun.
不迷失自己的方法就是…
One way to remember who you are...
咋开门的？
How do you open this thing?
树立正确的英雄榜样
...is to remember who your heroes are.
我现在自己干
I'm doing things my way now.
万丈高楼平地起
Building from the ground up.
万事无捷径
There are no shortcuts.
我的天呀 你在搞什么？
Oh my God, what are you doing?
- 啥？我弄混了  - 我们有好多事儿要忙
- What? I messed it up. - We have a lot of things to do.
- 来吧！  - 好吧 好吧！
- Come on! - All right, Jesus!
嗨 艾玛
Hi. Emma Jennings.
稍等
One second.
亚当有客人
Adam, you have a visitor.
你好
Hi.
这地方不错
Nice place you have here.
我意思是指在布鲁克林区
I mean, for Brooklyn.
非常荣幸你能来
I'm glad you came.
一直收到一家新公司的职位邀请电邮
Kept getting e-mails about a job offer at a brand-new startup company.
为什么我没看见…
Why I didn't see that coming...
我们…
Yeah, we, uh...
我们真的需要你
We really need you here.
你们请不起我的
You couldn't afford me.
算你公司股份
Lots of stock options.
那你得更加把劲
You have to do better than that.
好
OK.
我真的需要你
I need you here.
我考虑考虑
I'll think about it.
走 我请你喝一杯
Come on, let me buy you a drink.
你说你喜欢桥那边的人的
You said you had a thing for bridge-and-tunnel.
这是你原话 艾玛
Your words. Emma.
那至少让我感谢一下你的大驾光临？
Can I at least thank you for considering my offer?
谢谢
Thank you.
我喜欢经过那大桥
I like being across the bridge.
那里才有家的感觉
Over here, it feels like home.
谢谢观影